all right so the first thing we're going
to install with Brew is Bash we're not
going to talk about bash versus esell
right now that's a separate video so get
on the command line
Maru oops we're not going to be able to
do Brew remember because it's in that
weird place opt home brew I push tab
there bin Brew now we have to do this
the first time because we haven't set up
our shell yet to know where the Brew
command line The Brew command is which
we are going to do but we're going to do
it after we get bash installed so we're
going to go ahead and use this
longwinded one uh if you're on an Intel
Mac it might be user local so op home
brew bin Brew install bash I think let's
try it so it's going to go get the bash
cask and download it uh disable this by
heavier blah blah blah all right so now
let's just see if it finds
bash uh bash
Dash uh
V oops no not that we don't need that
yet oh this is from my this is from my
bash yeah which you're not supposed to
know about
yet so so that so if you have a bash you
should be you should be good to go uh
man bash this is not going to be the
same bash
probably uh actually let's do well you
can do this you can do bash if you just
execute bash you should get a new bash
right now the question is which bash is
it though and I I think you're going to
need a new shell for that so right now
you don't know how to reinitialize your
shell so go ahead and stop your terminal
and restart it I don't ever do that but
this is the thing to do for now because
you don't know so we're going to go
ahead and open another terminal command
T and this
time uh we should be able to ex
bash and we should get bash here let's
let's see what what environment
variables we
have
uh I'm trying to I'm trying to figure
out which version of bash we actually
have um let's do a search I mean I know
one way but I want to see what you would
do if you found it what would you find
how can I know which version of
bash bash DV
usually Echo bash version all right so
Echo that's what I was going to do so
honestly I just wanted to make sure that
was there wasn't a better way so this is
3.2 and if you can go to a search to say
what is the most recent version of
bash most I'm still searching using not
using the terminal I do this from the
terminal so stay tuned if you want to
see videos about how to search from the
terminal it's way more effective so what
is the most uh
recent version of bash you this the kind
of thing you could ask chat GPT from the
terminal as well so this looks like it
did not find the bash that we wanted to
because our path is wrong so I think
we're going to probably want to do opt
Homebrew bin and I'm guessing that bash
got installed here which it did
and uh now let's Echo bash
version Echo bash
version and we get 5.2 so that is going
to be our new
shell uh and but that's that's how you
install that there um the hard part now
is to change our shell we're going to
need to do this account uh this this
this particular command now this this
change cell command is a is a Mac only
sort of thing I mean you can do it on
Unix as well other unises but it's
generally not you generally wouldn't do
this you would change Etsy password um
if you were doing this with Linux but
that's information you don't need to
know so right now let's just do this opt
home baru
bin bin
bash and that should get us where we
need to be
[Music]
uh
yeah I have
oopsie I have to try it again because I
have a really really long
password I
know
yeah uh
ah non-standard shell I'm going to have
to throw this video away
too it is totally a standard
shell yeah I don't know what's going on
with
that my Mac doesn't have that my other
Mac is is totally fine it finds all the
right
things didn't I do the
sudo super secret password does it have
to be Pudu
[Music]
H oh my
gosh the bad thing about having a good
password is it's really
hard changing shelf rout that was kind
of stupid but oh well
uh I guess we give it a user no I needed
to change it for rout anyway so I don't
use the change shell command I don't I
probably
should I usually use it in Etsy password
I change
it offn name shell user
yeah I thought you could change your own
shell can't you change your own
shell that's very
interesting all right let's try this
again all right there we go it
worked oh well I guess I'll leave all
that in there so now I have now bash is
my new shell Echo bash version thank you
for the help
everybody sorry I was such a a noob with
that but they've changed some things
with Brew the way Brew
Works uh sudu for I know I don't think
you should need sudu for the individual
user but um looks like that
took uh are not in your path bash in
this case yeah see bash bash used to
install packages in the right place I
mean Brew used to sell packages that
were that would resolve properly and I
I'm I'm struggling right now because the
new Brew doesn't do that so I'm glad I'm
struggling for people to see
it uh and it says the nonset shell
because it's not the Apple provider
version which is totally lame so I'm
glad you got to see my firstand
struggles and reaction to all of the
changes that they've made um I'm
definitely going to do a ranty video
about the difference
between uh the you know the shells and
Zell and Bash and how I think Apple's
got their head up their rear end uh with
regard to changing from The Bash shell
the reason they did it primarily by the
way is the licensing and legal
restrictions that no matter what tell
anybody tells you that's the main reason
they did it um so the the good news is
is that we actually have bash installed
we've got bash five on and we can now
start customizing bash beginning with
putting uh Brew into our path and we'll
start talking about what the path is um
to do all of that though we're going to
have to start slowly getting into what
does it mean to write shell script
what does it mean to write bash scripts
this is one of those chicken in the egg
scenarios it gets really messy and I
don't want you to be afraid of it but we
definitely are going to have to learn
how to code a little bit before we learn
to code and just in order to customize
the shell so we'll be doing some things
that are actually code um just to get
the shell bright and then we'll come
back later and we'll come to understand
that all that stuff that we wrote Into
the configuration files was actually
code and we can now use that to write
our own scripts for other things um
that's that's probably one of the most
challenging parts of getting started on
Unix and Linux is this um this notion
that you have to know how to script in
order to set up the shell that you're
going to use and so who where do you
start right and um I'm going to save the
rest of the conversation about that to
later the the spoiler is that you
usually have to take somebody else's
preconfigured setting
and just adopt them and trust them and I
mean people have been doing this for
years and then you you gradually learn
how to customize them and and make them
your own and that that has been a WR a
passage for Unix people since the
beginning of Unix so don't be afraid of
that don't be afraid of making the
mistakes like I made and I'll end the
video there